nationalreview.com 2019-12-18

# Privacy Policy | National Review

_Updated: August 27, 2019_

At National Review we believe you should know what data we collect from you and how we use it. We also believe you should be able to make the best decisions about the information you share with National Review. That is the spirit behind this privacy policy.

* * *

**QUICK OVERVIEW OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

We encourage all users of the National Review website to read our privacy policy in full. But here’s a quick rundown of the key themes in this policy.

  * National Review is both a magazine and a website. We offer subscriptions to our magazine, including a digital version of our magazine that is available on our website. “Digital” subscribers need to login to our site to access the digital magazine and more. When logged in, you have full access via our Customer Care website to the information applied to your subscription account. (NRPLUS / digital users: To reach Customer Care, login, click MY ACCOUNT in the top right of the site, and then click the red Customer Care site link. Print users: [Click here](https://w1.buysub.com/servlet/CSGateway?cds_mag_code=NR1) to reach our Customer Care portal and enter your account number to access your Customer Care page.)
  * We receive personal information from you in a variety of ways. This information can come from what you give us directly, such as through a subscription, a newsletter sign-up, or a website comment. This information can also come from what you do not give us directly, such as data gathered by third parties (including advertisers) based on your browsing habits.
  * We use your behavior while on the National Review website to serve you additional content that you might like. In other words, we match your content selections with similar selections that you have not yet read. We hope this makes your website experience more rewarding.
  * You can control the information you give us. You can manage all of the information relative to your subscription on our Customer Care website. (Print users: [Click here](https://w1.buysub.com/servlet/CSGateway?cds_mag_code=NR1) to reach our Customer Care portal and enter your account number to access your Customer Care page. NRPLUS / digital users: To reach Customer Care, login, click MY ACCOUNT in the top right of the site, and then click the red Customer Care site link.) You can unsubscribe from any e-mail series we send you. (You can do this directly within the e-mail.) You can opt out of targeted advertising as well (see the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/)).
  * We encourage you to contact us at privacy@nationalreview.com with any questions you might have about our Privacy Policy and our practices regarding your personal information. European Union citizens may also contact privacy@nationalreview.com to request information on personal data that is being tracked or stored. Note: National Review, Inc., does not track and/or store any personally identifiable information (PII) on non-U.S. and non-subscribed users.
  * By subscribing to any of our digital-product offerings you accept our terms and agree to be tracked via login and other on-site actions deemed appropriate by the Publisher to deliver you the digital service you have requested.

* * *

**GENERAL STATEMENT ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This privacy policy exists to help you understand how information submitted will be treated when you log on to and/or use our website (www.nationalreview.com).

This privacy policy applies only to www.nationalreview.com. This policy does not apply to information collected through any other website or to the practices of companies that National Review does not control. Please note that our site may contain links to other websites. For example, if you click on an advertisement on National Review and link to another website, then this privacy policy will not apply to any information collected on that website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites, and we recommend that you read the privacy policies of each website that you visit.

* * *

**GENERAL STATEMENT ABOUT DATA COLLECTION & TARGETED ADVERTISING**

The National Review website permits data collection for interest-based advertising. We and third parties may use cookies, web beacons or pixels, mobile ad identifiers, and other tracking technologies to facilitate site navigation, to better understand and improve our services, and to determine or improve the advertising shown to you on this website or elsewhere. We may use your information to facilitate the delivery of targeted ads and promotions on behalf of ourselves and advertisers on this website. This information may be combined with information collected across different websites, online services, and other linked or associated devices.

We and third parties may use technologies called beacons or pixels that communicate information from your device to a server. Beacons can be embedded in online content, videos, and e-mails, and can allow a server to read certain types of information from your device, know when you have viewed particular content or a specific e-mail message, determine the time and date on which you viewed the beacon, and determine the IP address of your device. We and third parties use beacons for a variety of purposes, such as analyzing the use of our services and providing content and ads that are of greater relevance to you.

You may opt-out of receiving targeted advertising by visiting websites operated by the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) and [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/).

* * *

**THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**The information you provide directly to us:**  
You are not required to provide information directly to us in order to view National Review. However, when you use certain functions of the website, such as when you register for certain services, access certain content or features, or directly contact us, we may ask you to provide information, including:

  * contact information, such as name, email address, postal address, phone number, and mobile number;
  * username and password;
  * information posted in community discussions and other interactive online features;
  * search queries conducted on the National Review website; and
  * correspondence you send to us.

**Information automatically collected when you visit and interact with the  National Review website:**  
When you visit and interact with National Review, certain information may be collected automatically, including:

  * your computer’s Internet Protocol (IP) address;
  * your browser type and operating system;
  * the web pages you were visiting immediately before and after you came to the Site;
  * activities within community discussions;
  * web pages and advertisements that you view, and links that you click on;
  * your bandwidth speed and information about the software programs that are installed on your computer;
  * aggregated data about email click-through rates and user video viewing;
  * standard server log information; and
  * information collected through HTML cookies, Flash cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies.

**Information we collect from other sources:**  
We may access information about you from third-party sources and platforms (such as social networking sites, databases, online marketing firms, and ad targeting firms), including:

  * if you access third-party social networking services (such as Facebook Connect or Twitter) through the National Review website, your username and connection lists for those services;
  * demographic data, such as age range, gender, and interests;
  * advertisement interaction and viewing data, such as ad click-through rates and information about how many times you viewed a particular ad; and
  * unique identifiers, including mobile device identification numbers, that can identify the physical location of such devices in accordance with applicable law.

Please note that we may combine the information that we collect with information we obtain from third-party sources.

* * *

**HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**E-mail Communications:**  
We may use the information that we collect to send you e-mail communications, such as editorial updates, information about your account or changes to National Review, and promotional messages about our own or our marketing partners’ products and services. If you signed up for one of our e-mail newsletters, we also will send you the newsletter that you requested.

**Advertising:**  
In order to provide our readers with free access to our content, we display advertisements on the National Review website, many of which are targeted based on information about you. For example, using information collected through cookies, web beacons, and other sources, we may use demographic data or information about your online activities or interests to display targeted advertising that may be relevant to your preferences. Through this process, advertisers reach National Review visitors who are most interested in their products, and you see advertising for products or services in which you may be interested.

Third-party advertisers and advertising platforms also may serve targeted ads on the National Review website. Please remember that the information practices of third-party advertisers or platforms collecting data on our site are not covered by this privacy policy.

**User Accounts:**  
To provide you with an open, but also civil, discussion forum, we track user involvement in our community discussions. For example, we may delete comments per our comment-moderation guidelines in order to maintain civil and open discussions.

**Request Fulfillment:**  
We may use the information that we collect to fulfill your requests for products, services, and information. For example, we may use your contact information to respond to your customer-service requests or to enable you to participate in features on the site such as surveys, polls, sweepstakes, and message boards.

* * *

**INFORMATION SHARING**

National Review values your privacy, and shares information about our users only under certain circumstances. We will make information about you available to other companies, applications, or people in the circumstances listed below:

  * We may employ third parties to perform National Review-related services, including database management, maintenance services, analytics, marketing, data processing, and email and text message distribution. These third parties have access to your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf.
  * We may share information gathered from our subscribers with select third-party vendors who assist us and other parties with promoting and marketing products. This might include customer research, management of customer databases, promotional mailings or other targeted promotions. This information may include your name, address, or e-mail address. You may request at any time that we do not share your name, address, or other information with these third parties by e-mailing [webmaster@nationalreview.com](mailto:webmaster@nationalreview.com).
  * If you choose to engage in public activities on the site, such as posting comments on community message boards, any information you submit can be read, collected, or used by others. Please exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal **i** nformation in public activities or submissions.

Please note that third parties may independently collect data about you, including your IP address and information about the websites you visit and the links you click, through cookies, clicks on links, or other means when you visit or view ads on the National Review website.

* * *

**THIRD-PARTY SERVICES**

To customize your experience on the National Review website and to simplify our registration process, we provide you with the opportunity to access or interact with third-party services, such as Facebook and Twitter. When you connect to the site through these third-party services, we may share information about you with these third-party service providers and they may share data about you with us.

In addition, if you connect to a Facebook account, your experience on the site may be personalized. For example, you may automatically see what stories are popular in your network, and what your friends are saying about particular stories.

Please note that you may disconnect third-party accounts at any time. To modify your Facebook privacy settings, click [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/325807937506242). To modify your Twitter privacy settings, click [here](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20169886).

Please remember that we do not control the privacy practices of these third-party services. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of all third-party service providers.

* * *

**YOUR ACCOUNT**

**Deactivating your account:**  
You can deactivate your account at any time (please use the service through which you signed in). When you deactivate your account, your user profile will be disabled, but your public comments will remain on the site. National Review has no responsibility to take down, remove, or edit any of your public activities or any submissions that are a result of your public activities.

**Cookies and other technologies:**  
As discussed above, cookies and other technologies, as well as third-party advertisers, may collect information about you.

  * _Cookies:_ You can change your browser settings to reject all cookies, accept only certain cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. Please note that you may need to renew these settings if you delete your cookies after these preferences are made. These settings also may not apply if you are using a different computer or Internet browser.
  * _NAI:_ In addition, many third-party advertising networks are members of the Network Advertising Initiative. To opt out of having information collected by NAI member companies used for behavioral advertising, to obtain information about the technologies these ad networks might use, and to view information regarding their privacy policies, please go [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).
  * _Flash Cookies_ : You can control how Flash cookies are used by visiting the Adobe Macromedia site, located [here](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html). Adobe enables you to allow some Flash cookies from certain websites, limit Flash cookies’ storage capacity, and disallow Flash cookies altogether. In addition, if you use Mozilla Firefox for your Internet browser, you can download the BetterPrivacy add-on to automatically delete your Flash cookies every time you close your browser.

If you opt out of these technologies, you will continue to see advertising displayed on National Review, but the advertising may not be targeted to your interests.

Please remember that we do not have access to, or control over, advertiser or service-provider cookies, and the information practices of third parties are not covered by this privacy policy.

* * *

**CONFIDENTIALITY & SECURITY**

We limit access to contact information about you to employees or service providers who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information to provide products or services to you or in order to do their jobs. We also have adopted commercially reasonable technical, physical, and administrative procedures to help protect information about you from loss, misuse, and alteration.

Please note that no data transmission or storage can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure. We want you to feel confident using the National Review website, but we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us.  

* * *

**ADDITIONAL INFORMATION FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

**Subscriptions and Memberships** : By clicking “Join Now” or “Subscribe” or “Renew” for any National Review subscription or membership, you agree to our [Terms of Service](https://www.nationalreview.com/terms-of-service/), [Privacy Policy](https://www.nationalreview.com/privacy), and your California Privacy Rights (listed below). You also agree that we may share your information with third parties for marketing purposes. For instructions on how to opt out of such sharing, please review opt-out details in this Privacy Policy above.

**Your California Privacy Rights** : Residents of California may request a list of third parties to which certain personal information (as defined by applicable California law) obtained through a Digital Service was disclosed by National Review during the preceding year for those third parties’ direct-marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and want such a list, please contact us at National Review, Attn: Privacy, 19W 44th Street, Suite 1701, New York, NY 10036. For all requests, you must state “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. In your request, you must attest to the fact that you are a California resident and you must provide a current California address for our response. Please also indicate in your request the name of the Digital Service to which your request applies. Please note that we will not accept requests via telephone, e-mail, or by facsimile, and that we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or that do not have complete information.

**Do Not Track** : At this time National Review does not take steps to respond to browsers “Do Not Track” signals as no uniform standard to respond to such signals has been developed at this time.

* * *

**PRIVACY-POLICY CHANGES**

We may update this privacy policy at any time to reflect changes in our practices and service offerings. If we modify this privacy policy, we will update the effective date below. We will notify you of any material changes in the way we treat your information by placing a prominent notice on our site or sending a notice to the primary e-mail address specified in your account.
